I like to show everyone how to make ice cream
easy ways as well as hard ways but in today's
video I'm going to show you how to use flavored
coffee syrups like these to make amazing ice cream
yes you can use coffee syrups like
this to make amazing ice cream,
you can use the sugar-free ones too but you
still then need to do a balance to make sure
the recipe is right. These are loaded
with sugar this is let me have a look...
66% sugar, 75% sugar etc etc but we
can use this to an advantage because
as a science-based ice cream Channel,
we can do some calculations and make
sure that everything tallies up really
well plus we get the flavor of the syrup
that we're using. So let's get stuck in
I'm going to use one of these and ....
it's pistachio time, so pistachio
ice cream using moanin syrup.
It's actually like 2 days later now, hence
the T-shirt change, pistachio ice cream,
monin syrups ,yeah they're really easy to use so
as I said you just got to account for the sugar
and some of them will make the base curdle
there was a way around that but you just got
to be careful so let's get the stuff we need
start to start with we're going to weigh out
our ingredients in grams as we normally do because
that's the way you should weigh things but I will
put cup measurements on the screen for those that
prefer to use cups so let's get some ingredients
in the pan we're going to start with 344g of 2%
milk to that we are going to add 317g of 33 %
whipping cream and we're going to get this ready
because we're going to use a stabilizer we're
going to help this along because a stabilizer if
you in short ,61g of sugar into this little pot,
if you're unsure as to whether you want
to use a stabilizer in your ice cream,
the easiest thing to to consider is how long is
it going to take for you to eat your ice cream if
it's going to take a while then you should use a
stabilizer something like guag gum we're going to
add our stabilizer into that I'm going to use an
off to shelf stabilizer I like to use different
ones in every recipe because I can and 1.5g of
stabilizer if you use it if you don't don't add
it you don't have to if you don't want to our
stabilizer in with our sugar stir that together
stabilizer also helps to create a much better
texture because it basically just thickens and
joins certain molecules together milk for example
2% milk that is 98% water cream 33% cream that
is 66 reoccurring percent water, there's a lot of
water in ice cream if you don't stabilize that it
can become quite icy and that's why when you go to
a lot of scoop shops Etc or you make other recipes
from other people online it's a bit [__] I make
recipes that aren't [__] less jabber we got that
we're going to put in invert sugar you can use
any invert sugar you like corn syrup golden syrup
glucose syrup dedicated invert sugar um from a
company like Sosa is absolutely fine, 72g of this
72g. Corn syrup is just a product made out of
sugar so it's sugar that is boiled down and is
now a mixture of sucrose and fructose it's a
natural thing honey is the same thing by using
an invert sugar you're using the different
chemical structures of the sugar to create a
different texture in your ice cream in an ice
cream that will go hard then you can make it
softer but by including Inver sugar the fructose
which is just a natural type of Sugar by the way
will reduce the freezing point it will actually
change the texture of the ice cream make it kind
of chewy softer lots of things you can do with
sugars um skim milk powder right we got that so
we're going to add in our skin milk powder
into here of which we need 52g and we have
this we're going to weigh this out before we get
going because we want to do something else first
our pistachio monin syrup 95g and one more
ingredient, one whole egg but we're going
to put these in separate we need to
get this warmed up so let's get it
on hob we're going to turn our hob on and
we're going to just mix in this milk powder
like so and into that we're going to add in our
sugar with uh nearly dropped the egg managed to
catch it there with our stabilizer just get that
stirred in because now we're going to add in our
egg and break that up and stir that in
finally our moanin pistachio syrup so with
all that in because we got stabilizer
we're going to bring this up to 80c
we're just going to have to stir it constantly
because we've got our egg in there it will only
take a couple of minutes so I'll come back once
that's done as we start to get up to temperature
we need to make sure we keep this agitated we
don't want to cook that egg into scrambled egg
so we're just going to keep stirring it we're
pretty much there now anyway I'm going to turn
the heat off and take it off the hob careful
when you're using eggs I don't like temp
eggs the old fashioned way I've spoke about this
before I'll put a link on the top of the screen
here which is about eggs and how they used in
ice cream most places tell you to temper eggs the
oldfashioned way because that's how restaurants
do it uh when you're working in a restaurant you
do not have the time to stand in front of the
hob like this and stir something constantly you
don't have the time that is why they do it the
way they do that is why they bring up the rest
of the ingredients to temperature temper the egg
yolks like that pour it back in you got a very
short window then where you need to stir when
you're at home you have the luxury of taking as
long as you want so you can put the egg yolks or
whole eggs in this case straight in the pan and
just bring it up to temperature all you need to
do is just keep it agitated because if you don't
that egg will scramble so with our mixture now
completely homogenized we're going to put it in a
container like that if you're unsure as to
whether you have succeeded with your eggs look
in the bottom of your pan and you will see no bits
that is the reason that you should do it like this
and not the oldfashioned way that is now going to
go into the refrigerator to completely cool down
and then we'll Churn it as normal this is a really
nice simple ice cream to make once it's completely
chilled take it out of the fridge and get it in
your ice cream machine to churn this will work
in the Ninja creamy too so once it's churned take
it out and load up your containers and let's get
some of this glorious moaning syrup pistachio
ice cream dished up and see what it looks
like as you can see it Scoops really
really well it has perfect texture
perfect consistency it looks
incredibly creamy smooth finish
Mouse watering just looking at it I can
smell the pistachio looming out of the
bowl delicious I mean comparing this to a
real pistachio ice cream it it's not quite
the same you don't have that real pistachio
flavor there's a slight artificial flavor to
this but that's not the point of this video the
point of this video is to take any moaning syrup
I don't know where they all are over there
is to take any coffee syrup and turn it into
an ice cream of all the different flavors
of coffee syrup out there you've got this
huge selection available that you can turn into
ice cream from Irish Cream pistachio hazelnut
just there raspberry marshmallow toasted
marshmallow vanilla butterscotch all of
those options now available to you the flavors
are not are not uh perfect it's not the point
it's just how do we make really good ice cream
with whatever is available to us I think this
is about $20 Canadian about 15 GBP you know
somewhere between the two 167 USD but all of
that you you're going to get you know I think
this is a 7 this is one liter so you're going
to get 10 batches of ice cream out of that so
works out really cheap you know nice and easy
so anyway thanks very much for watching hope
you enjoyed this little hack on how to use
coffee syrups to make delicious ice cream give
it a try let me know what you think thanks for
much for watching don't forget to like And
subscribe I'll see you next week [Music]
oh [Music]